It's time for us to talk about loop
engineering. I was hoping this would
just blow over after a couple weeks. I
was hoping a cracked engineer would call
this stupid phrase what it really is,
but no one has. So, I'll do it myself.
Forget about loop engineering. It's the
wrong way to think about building
valuable software with agents at scale
consistently. Loop engineering is a
terrible rebrand of the software
development life cycle. It's as unclear
as it is hype-filled. In this video, we
simplify loop engineering and call it
what it really is. If you understand
this concept properly, we're going to
break down in this video, [music]
you'll accelerate far ahead of the AI
industry. Clarity and simplicity of
information gives you [music] speed and
performance in your work. It's much more
valuable and helpful to think about
building with [music] agents as if
you're building developer workflows
inside your software factory. Your props
[music] go into your software factory. A
specific workflow runs. Each workflow
[music] is a combination of code plus
agents and then your results [music]
come out. Forget about loop engineering.
Focus your valuable engineering time and
tokens on building AI developer
workflows.
So, first off, who am I to go up against
big ideas from AI engineers like Boris
Churnney from Anthropic and Peter
Steinberg, now from OpenAI? If you
already know who I am and the work I've
done, or you don't care, skip to this
timestamp. My name is Dan Eisler aka
Indie Dev Dan. I'm a software engineer
with over 15 years of EXP. I started out
building Adobe Flash games with Action
Script 2 and three with my brothers. I
interned at Blizzard and then I quickly
moved into the finance and accounting
space programming in C, TypeScript,
Python, God awful React and God bless
Evanu for creating Vue. I was AI coding
before anyone had a name for it with
tools like Ader and classic models like
GPT3.5 Turbo, GPT4, and Sonnet 3. Tools
and models you've probably never heard
of or used. I own the domain name
agenticengineer.com
where thousands of engineers you've
heard of from companies you know have
improved their agentic engineering
thanks to information products I've
built by hand. But anyone can pick up a
domain name and create a course though,
right? Sure. I also have an irrefutable
trail of code and content for engineers
on GitHub and this YouTube channel every
single week for years now. You can see
myself and engineers that follow this
channel consistently ahead of the curve
of the AI industry. I don't just farm
news for views like every other tech
content creator. On this channel, we
think, plan, and build. Every few
months, it's important for me to sit
down and say this. I'm not a content
creator. I'm a software engineer that
does content creation on the side. Why?
Because this technology is too valuable
to fall into the hands of a lucky few.
And yes, I sell courses. And yes, I
benefit from it. Big whoop. Don't do
anything you're great at for free.
Welcome to capitalism. Enough about me.
I don't show up here every single Monday
to gloat and talk about myself. I show
up here to give engineers like you an
advantage you can use to accelerate your
career, your work, your business, your
engineering in the age of AI, no hype.
So, forget about loop engineering and
focus on this instead. There are now
three actors of value creation for
engineering work. The engineers like you
and I, there are the agents and there's
the code. Knowing when and where to
place each of these is the name of the
game of agentic engineering. And you
might be thinking, where is he going
with this? How does this relate to loop
engineering and developer workflows?
Stick with me here. We're going to work
up to it. If you master the
fundamentals, you'll master the
compositions. Everyone in their AI
psychosis seems to forget code is fast,
always runs the same way unless you tell
it not to. And guess what? It costs
nothing. There are no token costs
associated with code. the thing that
truly moves at light speed. There's a
hidden cost to implementing every single
one of these actors of value creation.
Everyone's talking about agents. We're
all well aware of the cost of engineers,
but code is the unsung hero of all of
this. Consistent value creation creates
consistent business value. And out of
these three, code is the most reliable
by miles followed by engineers [music]
and then agents. So let's start with the
most basic developer workflow.
An engineer prompts an LLM and the
engineer reviews the result. This is the
simple foundation that makes up every
single loop, every single workflow,
every single piece of work moving
forward. Now, of course, we're not just
using the LLM anymore. In this central
node, we have an agent. Insert your
favorite agent. Insert your favorite
model. It doesn't matter anymore. It's
about the workflow that you and I
execute every single day. Great. Let's
scale it up. Now, we have code, agents,
and engineers all involved in the
process. We're building up to more and
more advanced developer workflows.
You'll notice something really important
here. We now have code. In this case,
we're just running a llinter. We have a
condition. If the llinter fails, the
results go back into our build agent. If
they're successful, it passes. This
condition and this routing back to our
build agent creates our first loop.
Hence the term loop engineering. But
loop engineering is too simple. It's too
inaccurate. And there's a lot more to
this story. So what comes next? How can
we continue to enhance our developer
workflow to get better results? We can
of course add more deterministic code.
Now we have multiple pass fill
statements routing back into our build
agent. Your codeex, your cloud code,
your pi coding agent, whatever your
agent harness is. This is the foundation
of what it means to build with agents.
Now you have three actors in this.
Engineers, agents, and raw code. You
have to leverage them all in the right
location at the right time. Here we're
adding a code formatter. It doesn't
matter what language you're in. linting
your code, formatting your code, type
check your code, and then keep scaling
up the validation loops to run back into
your agents. Once again, you'll see here
these conditions is what makes up what
is called the loop. But there's a lot
more going on here. This is really a
workflow of how information travels
within a system. Okay, keep scaling it
up. What comes next? We can add more
code. A very valuable piece of code here
is testing your code. So test. Now we
take all these results, feed it back
into our build agent over and over and
over until the results all pass. And
that gives us our final engineering
review. You'll notice a pattern here.
You and I always show up at the ends.
These are the two constraints of a
gentic engineering. Prompting, also
known as planning, and reviewing, also
known as validation. If you're a gent
engineering at scale properly, you're
showing up at the beginning and the end
with a few exceptions. Your AI developer
workflows start simple like this, but
they should continue to grow. Real
engineering work looks a lot more
complex than this, [music] right? What
do we do next?
We can scale all of our testing, all of
our validation, all of our linting, all
of our type checking into a single test
agent. So now we're scaling our compute
to scale our impact. We're adding
compute to add confidence. Now you can
imagine we've handed this test agent all
the things we want to do to test. And if
something goes wrong, we send the
context back to the build agent. If it
passes, the engineer reviews and then we
can ship the deliverable. We can ship
the code. All right. So notice a couple
themes working here. As you scale up
your developer workflows, you add agents
and you add code. But what you don't
want to add is more engineering effort
outside of building the system that
builds the system. Let's keep scaling
this up. Let's add planning to the
workflow. You're very familiar with
these ideas, right? We're building
workflows. These are all steps that you
and I, the engineer, used to take and
used to execute ourself, right? We would
plan work, we would build the work, we
would test the work, we would then have
another engineer review the work, and
then we would finally ship it into
production. All right? It's a developer
workflow and all we've done here is
added AI to it. The loops is just one
piece of it. You can call it loop
engineering but it's inaccurate and it's
not encapsulating the whole picture. If
we have loop engineering, we need to
have condition engineering and then we
need to have function engineering and
then we need to have a word plus
engineering for every type of control
flow inside of the software development
life cycle which is going to go on
forever. Okay. So a very popular pattern
is to push each one of your agents into
their own work tree. This creates
isolation. This creates parallelism.
This lets you do more work in parallel.
And there's a nice side effect here
where the agents don't trip over each
other. So, guess what we're going to do?
We're going to write another prompt. And
this time, we're going to write a prompt
into a piece of code that's going to
build our work trees. All right. So,
here we have a deterministic piece of
code that's going to kick off multiple
work trees based on the prompt. And then
we're going to execute several different
agents running in line. So we have once
again scaled our compute to scale our
impact. We have multiple work trees
running our plan, build, test, review,
merge, ship pipeline, our developer
workflow. The workflow you and I used to
go through as engineers building by
hand. Now we have AI, hence AI developer
workflows. And this is really important
to think through. This is where you
should focus in your engineering time.
How can I combine the three actors of
value creation, engineers, agents, and
code to create workflows that execute
large amounts of work on my behalf, on
behalf of my company, on behalf of your
users and products? That's the name of
the game. Okay, so great, we have work
trees. Work trees are um like I like to
say, a great place to start, not a great
place to end. There are a lot of
problems with work trees. We can do one
better by giving our agents each their
own sandbox. Okay? So instead of
spinning up work trees, we're now giving
every single agent their own computer,
right? Their own agent sandbox to
operate. Because once you do this, you
have full isolation. You yourself can
jump into the sandbox to look at the
work, look at the result, look at the
web page, look at the tests, look at the
application, whatever you need to do, do
your review. And then of course once all
the work comes back in you merge and you
ship. So once again notice the three
actors of value creation working
together. And notice how your ability to
create these AI developer workflows is
your ability to scale your impact with
agents. It's designing these AI
developer workflows that is the most
value accreative thing an engineer can
do. Hence the term I like to say on the
channel all the time. You want to be
building the system that builds the
system. Okay? As you can see here,
you'll start to see similarities in
these workflows with a lot of work
you've seen, a lot of work that you've
done, and hopefully work that you're
building into your teams, your
co-workers, your business, your tools
themselves. Okay? We're just getting
started, [laughter] right? Uh real work
gets more and more complex. And this is
the art and science of agentic
engineering. So, let's keep scaling it.
A very common thing to do as you
continue to progress is to set up a
conbon board, some type of ticket
system. Input comes from all over your
organization, right? It comes from
support, it comes from product, and it
comes from engineers, right? So now
things get interesting because now we
have a new unit, a new wrapper around
our code, right? We have some type of
ticketing system. And so once again,
like there's this really important
delineation that I make inside of
tactical agentic coding. And it is this
idea of the agentic layer. The agents,
the prompts, the skills, the system
prompts that wrap your application are
the thing to be focused on right now.
Because when you put those together with
your code, with your system, with your
entire team and your organization, you
are agentic engineering. Agentic
engineering is not just about the
agents. Spoiler alert, it's about your
team and most importantly your users and
putting together the most valuable stack
of the actors of value creation. Okay,
so conbon board, right? Let's let's jump
into this. What does this look like?
Okay, so for most teams, your tickets
are then analyzed by your engineer who
actually knows what's going on and
they'll translate that into a mid to
low-level prompt that you'll then pass
into another full workflow, another
agent sandbox. But some advanced teams
if you're teaching your organization how
to write prompts well enough and as
models become more capable uh you can
skip your engineer input prompt here
right because your engineer's job should
be building the system we act on the
meta layer we act on the layer that can
compound across our organization okay so
advanced teams can skip the engineering
prompt if this step is done properly all
right but so you know this is code right
conbon boards it's just code there are
no agents there then we enter the meat
of our workflow where we run code to
move that ticket into planning. Guess
what happens next? Our agents take over
the pipeline. We'll have a scout agent
look for all the code, look for all the
tickets, look for all the documentation,
look for previous spec files, and then
it'll hand that to a plan agent. Right?
So, we're splitting up our searching and
our planning between two agents here.
Once again, scaling compute, scaling
impact. And after that happens, you
know, plan phase is complete. So, we run
code to update our ticket to move
context to do some specific work inside
of our sandbox. And then of course our
build agent kicks off. And you know what
happens from here. You've done it a
million times yourself. And now with
agents, your build agent moves it into
testing after it's done. And then your
test agent tests, right? This individual
loop, which is just one part of the
developer workflow, executes until the
result passes. And then we're going to
run our CI/CD. And guess what can happen
here? This can pass or it can fail and
go right back to the build agent to
resolve the issues. All right. And then
we get outside the sandbox. Engineer
reviews the code. You know what this
looks like now? Fail, pass, ship. Right?
So you can see this is much more than
just prompt engineering. It's much more
than context engineering. It's much more
than harness engineering. It's much more
than loop engineering. This is about how
teams move as an organism with all the
actors inside. Okay? And if you're a
small solo dev shop, same deal, right?
It's about how you and your agents work
together with code to generate valuable
results. But this isn't the end. The
future of engineering is vast. Okay,
let's keep pushing this. What happens
next? Let's let's imagine another
scenario here. Imagine you have a
support crisis. Production is down.
Okay, production has crashed. So, what
AI developer workflow do you have
planned in your organization right now
when production goes down? How are you
leveraging engineers, agents, and code
to resolve this issue and to stop your
business from leaking cash as your
production system is down? Let's walk
through it, okay? Because we've thought
through this, right? We've designed,
we've architected the AI developer
workflow to account for this situation.
Support files a ticket. In our case
here, this goes right to Slack. It goes
right to Teams, goes right to your
communication channel, and one of your
cracked engineers picks this up
immediately. What do they do? They
prompt a scout agent that routes right
into a hot fix agent. Your hot fix agent
has a specialized set of mental memory.
It's an agent expert that knows and is
prioritized to get things fixed. It's
not doing things the right way. It's not
doing things the fancy way. It's not
optimizing anything. It's getting the
fix out ASAP and nothing else. This is a
surgical hotfix agent, a custom agent
that you have specialized, that you've
templated your engineering into. Now,
what happens here? Human in the loop.
This is a hot fix. We need to know the
solution is going to work. So you put in
human effort, right? You use engineering
effort to approve or reject. This
creates a single loop. All right? If we
approve, guess what happens? We're going
to build up a bunch of sandboxes to run
the solution in parallel. And guess
what? We're using multiple sandboxes. I
want the first fastest agent that has
the solution to win. Okay? Whatever your
compute budget is, you'll scale this up.
You'll scale this down. If you're in a
production system that's complex, you
might want three, five, 10 agents
running and racing toward a solution in
their own agent sandbox, you don't care.
You have the compute, you've done the
agentic engineering to scale your
impact. And guess what happens here? You
already know what happens. It runs its
individual loop in their sandbox. And
then it passes or fails. If it fails, it
goes right back to your hot fix agent
and to you to resolve. And of course, if
it's all successful, you the engineer
validate it and you get the hot fix
shipped ASAP. Okay. A question for you
and your organization. Do you have an
agentic workflow for production crashes?
Can you get that resolved in record time
using the three actors of value creation
in the age of agents? Engineers, agents,
and code. All three. Okay, this
continues to scale and scale and scale.
Let's push these workflows further.
After some point, what you get is a
structure like this.
And this is what really starts turning
into a software factory. Okay, you'll
see here we have many different types of
specialized agent sandbox workflows.
Some are for chores, one is for a bug,
one is for a feature, one is for this
hot fix that we just walked through. And
you get the idea here, right? Any
specialized AI developer workflow you
need can be built and routed to thanks
to your routing system. Okay, this is
the art and science of agentic
engineering, right? This is all of it
put together. The loops are just one
small piece of this picture. I hope you
can see that. Now, in all this is a
great level of prompt context harness
engineering. There are a million ways to
do this. There are a million different
multi- aent orchestration patterns to
build into this. The key here is this.
is that you have the right combination
at the right time to push engineering
work through end to end with agents with
code with engineers. Okay, I know I'm
repeating myself. I'm doing it on
purpose. Most success in any domain is
about doing a few things and saying a
few things and focusing on a few things
over and over and over. Let's walk
through a full software factory. You can
imagine how this looks, right? Let's
keep with a conbon ticket example. Now,
anyone can file a ticket. This is a
feature. This is a bug. This is a chore.
Advanced teams are going to skip wasting
engineering time transferring your
conbon ticket into a low-level or
mid-level engineering breakdown of what
needs to happen. Advanced teams are
going to go right to kicking off a
software factory. The moment your conbon
ticket lands, once the factory starts,
it's going to mark that ticket in
progress and move it. And now we have a
factory router agent. This could just be
a simple LLM call. This could be some
deterministic code. The exact nodes are
up to you to decide, but you get the
idea here. I'm going to throw a factory
agent here to intake the results. Do a
quick look at the codebase, understand
what AI developer workflow we need to
execute for the system. First though,
we're going to set up a sandbox. We're
not limiting our agents anymore. We know
that agents are going to continue to
expand. This is what the CPU crunch is
all about. CPUs are getting wiped off
the board outside of scaling RL and
other ML engineering related work. Agent
sandboxes are going to, I can guarantee
you this, be the majority of computers
out there in the world. You and I will
be using fewer and fewer devices while
our agents continue to scale up and use
more sandboxes. Okay, but set up the
sandbox. After that, our agent has
already decided what type of workflow we
need to get the job done at the best
price, at the best performance, and at
the right speed. Because as you likely
know, you're not going to run your hot
fix AI developer workflow or your
feature AI developer workflow where
you're scaling out your very best
agents. Maybe your build agent is a
workhorse model, but your planner and
your scouters are going to be
state-of-the-art model so nothing gets
missed. Of course, there's a whole slew
of multi- aent orchestration work that
can happen here. But the whole point is
you're not going to deploy your heavy AI
developer workflows for a chore, right?
for your chore. Throw a single agent at
this with a workhorse model, maybe even
a lightweight model. Build it, run the
lint, run the CI/CD, engineer reviews
it, and ship it out. We'll talk about
ZTE in a second, but the best teams are
going to start dropping off engineering
review because they've built the best
system possible that they know is going
to execute for them. But every single
unique workflow is unique for a reason,
right? There are multiple workflows you
want to build out here, multiple AI
developer workflows you should be
building out, not just one. I'll give my
recommendation some really, really great
practices you can use when building
these out in a moment here. But the
general rule of thumb is just to start
simple. Once you start scaling this up,
what you're going to end up with is a
software factory. A software factory
that can operate your application as
well. And if you're doing it right,
better than you and your engineering
team. This is why all your effort, all
of your effort goes into this. Now, the
agentic layer, right? This is the al the
agentic layer, not the app layer. The
app layer is for your agents. The the
best engineering teams never touch the
product themselves. Okay, I know this
might be like controversial. Some
engineers are going to hate hearing
this, but the best teams are doing meta
work on the agentic layer. They're
building the system that builds the
system. That is the central thesis
inside of tactical agentic coding.
Thousands of engineers know that and
you're going to figure it out too sooner
or later. Okay, that doesn't mean you
can't jump into the app to do work. But
when you have a successful product
scaled with users, the name of the game
is this. Building a software factory
that operates everything better than you
alone could, better than code alone
could, and better than agents alone
could. Right? Three actors of value
creation, agents, engineers, code. Where
does that all lead us? It leads us to
the simple conclusion that it's not a
loop you're after. It's an AI developer
workflow. Okay, you might be, you know,
listening to this and thinking, but you
you drew a million loops. Like, isn't
this a loop? Fine. If you want to call
it a loop, I don't really care. I think
a loop is too constrained. If you're
going to call it a loop, we're going to
need if engineer, we're going to need
throw engineering. We're going to need
exception engineering, right? We're
going to need to name all these things
engineering. This is a developer
workflow. This used to be what engineers
did. Engineers used to decide if
something was a chore, if something was
a bug. We used to write the plan, we
used to execute it, so on and so forth.
But now we have a new tool and that's
all it is. It's a new tool. We have
agents to work with that gives us AI
developer workflows. Okay. So at the
highest levels of agentic engineering,
you're building software factories that
execute the right work and the right
combination of engineers, agents, and
code across your organization. Once you
really start to scale it up, you're
going to add your other teammates,
right? Your other team members from
other cross cutting concerns inside of
your business. But at the core of it,
the engineers are responsible for the
code. Okay? I think a lot of orgs are
going to have a a problem with this once
they start scaling in and adding other
team members, right? Especially ones
that can't write clear tickets for the
life of them. You've seen this a million
times, right? It's the most painful
thing when your product manager, your
your CTO, your your tech lead [laughter]
just writes a ticket and you have
to translate it, right? So there's
there's a lot of like, you know, people
organizational level work to be done
here. But you at the end of the day, you
know, you the engineer plus the agents
plus the code making up the AI developer
workflow. This is what it's all about.
This is where value is going to be
created at absurd levels, at absurd
scales. Because once you get this right,
here's the dirty secret of all software,
right? You already know it. Once you get
this right, you set up the right
guardrails, the right harness, right?
Again, prompt, context, harness
engineering, all of it. Once you do this
right, you have a repeatable workflow
that you can run tens, hundreds, and
thousands of times, delivering
consistent results to you over and over
and over again if you template your
engineering into the fabric of your AI
developer workflows. Okay? And so I've
been pushing against out of the box
agents for a long time. Um, you know,
specialization is the name of the game.
What is a product? What is a company?
Right? Unless you're a big tech giant,
like a product in a company is a a set
of people in technology that solve a
specific problem for a specific avatar
for a specific user for a specific
customer. By very definition is
specialization, right? Your expertise is
the most valuable thing you have now.
And you can template that into your
engineering. You can template that into
your AI developer workflows. All right,
this is the greatest leverage point of
agentic coding. It's building out these
full AI developer workflows that puts it
all together. Okay, and so you know once
again we are pushing away from vibe
coding. This is not vibe coding. Vibe
coding is not knowing how the system
works and it's not looking at how the
system works. Okay, agentic engineering
is knowing your system works so well you
don't have to look. And that is because
you the engineer have moved up a layer.
You're meta-engineering. You're
compounding an advantage by optimizing
the three actors of agentic engineering
engineer code agents into the right
developer workflow at the right time at
the right performance at the right price
with the right speed. And after time
you'll realize something really
important is that you'll be building AI
developer workflows into your products
for your customers right with your
customers as nodes and then as mentioned
with your companies every user that can
prompt into the system and receive
results out the system right you have to
design this system it's just another
system
so I've written hundreds and probably
thousands of these AI developer
workflows by now. So, let me give you
the oil of everything I've learned so
far with what I've seen and what I've
recommended to engineers as they're
building out their ADWs. Um, first off,
keep it simple. When you start building
these out, start with the simplest
workflow you can think of, right? And
typically that looks something like
this, right? After you get an agent
running, you prompt back and forth and
you're babysitting your agent. Everyone
knows what this looks like. Just let it
lent your code. You know, to be clear,
so that you can really feel this.
Separate this out. I'm not saying write
a skill, have your agent build, and then
at the bottom of the skill, run lint.
Separate this out. Use an agent SDK, run
a build agent, do work, and then run a
llinter. And when the llinter fails,
pass that back into the build agent with
the same session ID. You have to
separate your code and your agents.
Otherwise, you just have an agent
calling code. That's not what we want.
We want separation of concerns all the
way through. If that doesn't make sense
to you right now, don't worry. It'll
make sense once you start building it.
This is not a big skill where you run a
hundred different nodes of workflows.
There are massive testing, massive
validation problems with doing that. And
then what do you do after that? You add
a couple nodes, right? Start solving
real problems. Run your type checker,
run your llinter. If things go wrong,
funnel it back into your build agent.
What you'll notice here is that you're
starting to build a larger unit, a
larger system that operates without you.
You show the beginning and the end. the
two constraints of agent coding,
planning and reviewing, and your system
does everything else. Okay? And then
once you get to a certain point, you'll
start separating out your agents. You'll
start specializing your agents. Maybe
you want to separate your front end and
your back end. Maybe you want building
and testing. Again, the key here is just
that you separate the context out so
that your context can move between
individual agents and code. When you're
starting, remember KISS, keep it simple,
stupid. You can absolutely start with
pure skill-based workflows where it's
all one skill outside of the prompt and
the review. But as soon as you start
productionizing, as soon as you run to
get serious about your AWS, you must
separate code out of the skills because
that's still your agent running it,
right? You have to be super super clear
about those steps so that you can set up
the proper guard rails and information
flows in your AI developer workflows. My
next really big piece of advice here is
design your ADWs by doing the work
yourself first. For a lot of engineers,
this will sound insanely painful, but
you can like, you know, use your agent
in the terminal. Run the build workflow.
Do the testing, right? You can still use
your agent for that. I'm not saying do
it by hand. That would be a waste of
time now. But what I am saying is
whatever workflow you're setting up, run
it end to end. Step into each node
yourself. run the pass, run the
condition, watch the functions get
executed, do the review, and then do the
ship to production and then start
writing this all as a combination of
agents, engineers, and code. And I
recommend you take something like
mermaid. And you know, by the way, this
is like a adaptation of mermaid diagram.
I had an agent create using a plan build
test AI developer workflow in one shot.
I created a animated application which
is of course based on a mermaid diagram.
Okay, so shout out to mermaid. Shout out
to mermaid.live. But that's my second
piece of advice, right? Walk through it
all yourself first. Sit down pencil and
a piece of paper or use mermaid or use
whatever. Really sit down and like write
out your workflow. And then lastly, make
sure you're not just using agents,
right? Use agents and code. As I
mentioned, you can always start with
agents and skills, but as soon as you
start hitting production, as soon as you
want to get serious, move some of that
skill work into code. This is not just
about token cost. This is about
performance, reliability, and speed.
Again, everyone in their AI psychosis
has like forgotten that speed costs zero
tokens. There's no hallucination. It
does the exact same thing every time.
And it literally runs at the speed of
light. So, don't overleverage on agents.
Okay? Balance it out with actual code,
right? Code execution. And yes, there's
information orchestration. There is this
is what context engineering is. You're
going to need a place for all the
results in between each step. Yes, it's
going to take some time. Yes, it's going
to be a little knowing. Yes, during the
process, you'll wonder, I should just
throw this all in the skill. You'll be
wrong down the road. I can guarantee you
that. I've been there. Don't waste your
time doing other engineers have
already done wrong. Separate it out as
you scale this. Okay, so that's the big
third tip. Use agents and code. Okay,
because agents plus code beats either
alone, especially when you start really
scaling these into legitimately large AI
developer workflows that do serious work
for you and your organization. Why?
Because you're going to need to test
this node. You're going to need to test
plan into build. You're going to need to
test plan into build and to update the
status and to testing and to fail. This
is all still a system you the engineer
are responsible for. So keep using great
classic engineering patterns,
isolatable, decoupled, single interface,
right? All that stuff matters probably
even more, right? It matters even more
now because once you do it right and you
set up your AI developer workflow, it
gets multiplied hundreds and thousands
of times and your agents plus your code
can drive the outcomes for you. Okay?
So, you know, let's step away from the
vibes a little bit and let's step out
away from the AI psychosis a little bit
because if we're going to do serious
agentic engineering, you need to know
what's going to happen in your system.
So, if you made it to the end here, I
want to just say thank you for trusting
me. For everyone that's been with the
channel for a while, for years now, you
know, big shout out to you. I appreciate
you trusting me and following along this
massive journey of Agentic Engineering
that we're on. Um, if you want more, I
recommend you check out
agenticengineer.com, specifically
tactical agentic coding. As I mentioned,
I've been pretty early to a lot of these
ideas. In tactical agent coding, you're
going to hear a lot of what I just said
really broken down step by step across
eight lessons and then six additional
upgradable lessons if you're interested.
Okay, so the big idea here is AI
developer workflows. It's building
systems that build systems. We're not
touching the application layer anymore.
We're touching the agentic system, the
agentic layer that builds it on our
behalf. Okay? So, if you want to pay to
play, you want to get a big advantage
that again thousands of engineers that
you know of and have heard of at
companies you know the names of, they
are in here and they have gotten the
advantage and they are getting the
advantage, right? It's tactical agent
coding is the first eight lessons you
can upgrade to agentic horizon to get
some upgradeable ideas. really big idea
there is of course multi- aent
orchestration but agent experts is
turning out to be a massively banger
idea a massively important idea for
engineering in the age of agents if you
want to build true specialists that
outperform out of the box agent anyway
lots more in there's a very clear 30-day
refund before you start lesson 4. So if
you don't like my style or you're not
getting the core of it it's fine I don't
want you in here if you don't want to be
30-day refund before you start lesson 4.
This is going to be linked in the
description for you. Also, I recommend
if you vibe with the ideas here, if you
understand the ideas and you don't want
to jump in the tactical agent coding
right away, check out this blog. I'll
link in the description as well,
thinking in threads. It covers a lot of
the same ideas we've been discussing 99%
of everything I do here on this channel.
It's all free. It's out there for you to
understand and master agentic
engineering. If you made it to the end,
do me a favor, like this video, leave a
comment, and share it with your coworker
before your competition sends it to
theirs. You know where to find me every
single Monday. Stay focused and keep
building.