The AI industry wants one big winner.
GPT 5.6 Soul or Claude Fable 5. I'm not
picking one. Picking is the mistake. The
winning mindset in the age of AI is and
not or. Combine compute. Don't select
compute. Don't get me wrong, I maintain
a model stack to track the best models.
But when it comes to pushing the
frontier and getting real engineering
work done, you want teams of agents
working for you, not an unchecked lone
wolf. There's a simple yet powerful
pattern for this [music] that's existed
for years. Yesterday it was called
architect editor, prompt chaining, then
agent chaining. Today Devon open router
and [music] others call it model fusion.
Tomorrow, no matter what it's called
after you watch this video, it'll
[music] be another tool in your agentic
engineering toolbox. I've been running
this pattern for years across hundreds
and thousands of agents. You probably
have too without naming it. If you use
Model [music] Fusion properly, you're
combining the intelligence and the
context windows of your models. [music]
So, how do we tap into Model Fusion for
our agentic engineering work? Once
again, we don't vibe code. Instead, we
harness engineer with the PI coding
agent to build a powerful fusion [music]
harness.
There are three commands we'll use to
orchestrate our tight coordinated two
agent team. Opinion to get multiple
perspectives from our agents. Fusion to
combine and consolidate the best results
of our agents and auto validate to use
intelligent on the-fly validation to
improve on the second constraint of
agentic engineering review. We're going
to start with a couple of powerful
workhorse models cloud sonic 5, GPT 5.6
6 Terra and then we'll move up to the
state-ofthe-art models. Let's start
simple and move to the most valuable/
opinion lists the top three scikitlearn
models, use cases, pros and cons. So
when we fire this off, you're going to
see exactly what you would expect from a
fusion harness. We have two agents
working for us in parallel. This is two
unique perspectives that we wouldn't get
out of the box with any other agentic
coding tool. So if we scroll up here,
you can see exactly what happened. And
in fact, this tool is already giving us
insight into how these models perform
side by side. Terra blew through this
problem in just 4.5 seconds. 9K tokens
in, 300 out, 3 cents. Cloudset 5 took
double the time. 4K more tokens in, 4K
more tokens out, and it costs about a
cent more. We're nitpicking this small
prompt, but the key is that you can see
your agents side by side. Relativity is
the best benchmark. You can see we have
a nice breakdown here of the top
scikitlearn models. Random forest should
be the top answer and then they both
list a couple other ones. So let's go
ahead and combine the results into one.
One agent response is fine. Two agent
responses is good. Combining the
perspectives of two models is even
better. Let's do that now with /fusion
as table.md in your current working
directory. So once again, we're going to
use two models to do this work. They're
both going to execute on this, write
their table so that we have a concrete
result. But then something different
happens here. After the models do their
work, a new fusion agent using the same
model as our architect is going to pick
up this work and combine the responses.
So this is the fusion prompt applied
directly to agents in a dedicated agent
harness. Now we get to see where the
models agreed, what's the consensus,
what's the divergence and what was
discarded. This information is ultra
ultra valuable. Okay. So let's just
understand the results. What are the
best scikitlearn models according to
sonnet 5 and gpt 5.6 terra both agents
completely agreed here. This is great
random forest grade in boost logistic
regression. And you can see their
explanation of why. As engineers when
you're making decisions you want to
understand when to use technology and
you want to understand the pros and the
cons. Engineering is all about
trade-offs. Agents don't change that. At
the end of the day, you have to collapse
your work into a decision. And if you
want to make the best decisions, you
want the best compute available, giving
you their perspective, giving you their
input, giving you raw informations you
can use to build valuable software. You
can see we have a consensus. They both
all agreed on all these. We had a small
divergence. Both answers were
complimentary, not contradictory. So,
this is good. Our fusion model kept both
and there was nothing discarded. You can
imagine how powerful this can be when
you're making game time critical
strategic decisions for your engineering
work, but also for your business. Once
again, we're scaling our compute to
scale our impact. Now, let's use the
most powerful custom slash command we've
[music] built into our fusion
harness/auto
validate. implement an MVP of these
models with the smallest possible data
set to showcase their respective pros,
cons, and pros, consy, same dur. So,
super simple example we're working
through here just to showcase the power
of this fusion harness. What's happening
here? This is a unique agentic workflow
and it's built into the fabric of the
agent harness. When I type /a
valvalidate, a workflow inside the
harness kicks off that does this. You
can see here the builder is just
waiting. GBT 5.6 6 Terra is doing
nothing. What is it waiting for? It's
waiting for the validator to create a
validation gate. Cloud Sonnet 5 is
building out a validation gate right now
that proves that the work is done. With
this fusion harness with powerful
workhorse and especially
state-of-the-art models, we can do
something really incredible. Any prompt
we write can have a validation flow
written before the work is even started.
The validator is done now. It's written
a raw validation script that proves that
the work is done. It also has fail
commands to give feedback to our
builder. Our builder has very very
quickly built this out and really
impressed with the speed of the GPT 5.6
Terra and Luna models. Now what's going
to happen is really really cool. So the
validator immediately executed the
validation script. And you can see there
was no file created at all. And so the
validation failed, right? It was just
running this as its initial check. But
now this validation script is going to
run against the work from the builder.
So check this out. See if we got any
fails here. Pass pass. All passes, no
fails. Big shout out to 5.6 Terror.
Really powerful workhorse model. Kind of
sitting right next to Cloud Signet 5. I
think it's actually outperforming it by
a bit, especially when you take into
account the speed in which it gets work
done and the concision in which it does
it. This is all good. We can scroll back
up to the validation script that Sonnet
5 put out for us. Like look at all the
validations. Every one of these fail
statements is feedback for our builder
agent if something goes wrong. So you
can see it's running reg x. It's making
sure that these models exist, right?
Random force, gradient boost, logistical
regression. It's making sure that
everything is expected so that the
script actually works. And you know,
yes, these models can do more. They can
validate their own work. And you see
this when you run some of these
state-of-the-art models. They
automatically validate their work. They
run scripts, they compile, they run
llinters, they run tests, so on and so
forth. This is no different. We're just
putting the validation before the
execution. We're saying how can we know
for a fact this piece of code this unit
of work is done and we build that as a
script before anything runs. So this is
us fighting against the second
constraint of agentic coding. There's
two constraints of agentic engineering.
There's planning and reviewing the
fusion harness with /autov valalidate
lets us push past the current review
constraint. Last week we broke down loop
engineering and we focused on much more
valuable concepts software developer
life cycle ADWs and software factories.
If you haven't checked that video out,
definitely do that after you finish
watching this one. That one went viral
for a good reason. What we're doing here
with the fusion harness is we're
building on a single agent node. So the
entire harness would be a single agent
step. Literally once again scaling our
compute to scale their impact. Instead
of an individual agent running, we have
a tight team of agents validating their
work with each other, creating
validation scripts before anything runs.
As you can imagine, if this fails, the
validator is going to loop back into the
builder and say, "Hey, you messed this
up. Correct it." We're adding agents
into individual agent nodes to make up
three value creators in the age of
agents. It's engineers, its agents, and
it's raw code. Again, check out last
week's video to really understand the
shift away from loop engineering because
loop engineering is not encompassing
enough. It's a terrible rebrand of the
software developer life cycle. I hope
you can see why owning your agent
harness is so important. Let me just
like say this very loudly and clearly
again. Your tools directly limit what
you believe is possible. When you use
tools like the PI coding agent that are
customizable and extensible by design,
these mental false limits just fall away
very quickly. You're not waiting for
someone to deliver an update on some
feature that's blocking you. Hint hint,
cloud code, codeex, open code, so on and
so forth. I mean this all the way down
to like the fabric of the py coding
agent. It's meant to be customized. This
is the true value proposition of the PI
coding agent and software that adapts to
your will. There's a big ongoing debate,
ongoing concern that we're all prompting
all of our language models, all of our
agents and we're giving away our
company's data to these big AI labs,
anthropic, open AI, Gemini, so on and so
forth. This discussion of sovereign AI
is going to become more and more
important. We need to own our AI. We
need to have local compute where we can
run our language models knowing that our
traces are ours. The most valuable piece
of our work, the intelligence we're
deploying, all the work we're putting
into embedding our IP into agents is
getting gobbled up by these AI labs. You
know, make sure you like and subscribe
cuz next week I'm going to address the
question head on. Is anthropic and open
AI stealing our data while we pay for
it. That's an aside, a really important
aside that I've been thinking about more
and more and I want you to be very, very
aware of as you and I engineer in the
age of agents. Owning your agent harness
is ultra important. Now that you
understand this, now we're going to
really scale this to the max. Okay, so
let's throw a a harder, more realistic
problem [music] at our fusion harness.
Okay, so we're going to reset and now
we're going to run FHS fusion harness
state-of-the-art models. So let's
imagine a concrete problem. I have an
SQLite database inside of one of my
users devices among thousands of users.
SQLite is fantastic. There are over a
trillion SQLite databases around the
world. Knowing when to use SQLite versus
Postgress versus some NoSQL solution can
save you loads and loads of trouble. I
need to insert over a million rows into
an SQLite database across all my users.
Am I going to sit down and just prompt
this solution into a single agent?
Insert all 1 million rows into this user
into that user. Sure, we could. In this
scenario, we absolutely could. But I'm
thinking ahead. I know I'm going to have
to solve this problem again and again
and again for my business. And I don't
want a one-off vibecoded solution. I
want to solve every scenario in a fast
memory efficient way. So what we're
going to do here is use the fusion
harness to solve this problem. I want
the best state-of-the-art models near
their maximum capability. We're using X
high here on Clawed Fable 5 and X high
on GPT 5.6 Soul. Okay. So we have an
architect and a builder. And I want to
know what is the best way to insert a
million rows in a fast memory efficient
way. So, of course, same flow / opinion.
We'll paste in this prompt and fire it.
Feel free to pause to read the exact
prompt. We're just going to fire this
off. And now we have two
state-of-the-art models thinking through
this problem. I want the opinions of the
best compute available. As you can see
here, I am paying for this directly
through the PI coding agent. Both her
agents are going to run here and put
together a comprehensive answer for us.
This is a slash opinion from two of the
best models in the world right now. By
the time you're watching this, you might
have the new Gemini model. I actually
don't think that model is going to be
able to compete with Soul or Fable 5.
We'll see in the stats. We'll see in the
benchmarks. Regardless, it's going to be
more compute available to you and I to
build with and to combine our compute
against. We don't need single individual
winners. As you can see with the way
things are really working out in the AI
industry, there going to be many models.
There going to be many players. And
picking one is a mistake. Picking one
model, picking one model provider,
picking one agentic coding tool is a
mistake. Here's a crazy stat. I'm
building a new Asian harness nearly
every single day. The Fusion harness is
just one in a long line of custom agent
harnesses I built out to solve specific
problems to outperform any other out-
of-the-box agent coding tool. Something
to really think about if you're doing
real production work when you're
thinking about putting together your AI
developer workflows that contain
engineers code plus agents and your
individual agent nodes. You can put any
agent harness you need to or want to to
get extraordinary results. Cloud Fable 5
done. Took about 90 seconds. Soul
continuing to work. It looks like it's
actually running some tests. It's
actually kind of answering this question
for us [laughter] before we even get to
it. Fusion, of course, as you know, is
coming next. A good workflow I like to
use with the Fusion harness is, as
you've seen, ask for an opinion, fuse
the results of both opinion, and then
you run the auto validate kind of build
against it. Again, last week's video was
so important for many reasons, but as
you can see here, we're building out
micro software developer life cycles,
micro SDLC's. We're doing that inside of
this harness. You can think of / opinion
as like scout. You can think of /fusion
as our unofficial planning step. And
then, of course, autov validate is a
twoin one. We're testing and we're
building. Really curious to see how
valuable its answer is in comparison to
Fable. You can see it's already used 3x
the tokens to generate this result. It's
thinking a lot. We are in X high mode,
so it's to be expected. But regardless,
we're going to get the value of both
models. There are engineers using fusion
harnesses like this, using multiple
models, getting multiple perspectives,
and they're making better decisions. Let
me be super clear about that. Engineers
that can scale their compute to scale
their impact in a functional, useful
way, are making better decisions. This
ties really closely into the CEO agent
harness we built on the channel a couple
months back. Again, a custom agent
harness. We're customizing our
experience to get specialized results.
What is alpha? What is asymmetry? It's
specialization. It's doing what others
aren't yet. And so there we go. We
finally got that response. We got some
really, really insane speed ups from
both model. Fable got its top speed up
at uh 300x, but check this out. GPT 5.6
Soul found a 250 to 10,000X and another
400 to 2KX. Let's see if these models
are bullshitting or if there's some true
validity to what they're saying. These
models are just thinking. They're
reporting back in their own separate
thought chains. Let's fuse the compute.
Let's combine the context windows. Let's
combine the intelligence. Okay, so
fusion. And I'm going to paste this in
here. This is going to be a longer one,
but the idea here is that I'm having the
models design one benchmark script that
settles the bulk insert question for
good, right? On two axes, speed and RAM.
I'm kind of defining some parameters for
them. This is an Astral UV single file
script. Standard library only 1 million
rows, identical schema generation, blah
blah blah blah blah, right? Measure peak
RAM. You get the idea. Pause the video
here if you want to know the exact
details. But here we go. They're off to
the races. State-of-the-art models, the
best compute money can get you, the best
decision-making money can get you, the
best engineering money can get you,
minus actual engineers. Okay, [laughter]
that still holds true. But I will say as
a fact, the best engineers are using
these models together. The best
engineers are now like symbiotes with
these state-of-the-art models. They
don't make a decision without building,
testing, validating, ideulating,
planning with state-of-the-art models.
One of the highest leverage areas for
engineers now for agentic engineers is
decisionmaking and it's planning. And
guess what these models are great at?
Uh, increasingly so. Even if they don't
give you the right answer, they give you
a very concrete answer you can use to
increase your impact, to make better
decisions, to build better software, to
build better solutions for your users,
for your business, for your customers.
And so, they're off to it. This is going
to chew up lots of thinking tokens. You
can see here Fable is a lot more
decisive with its building, with it
planning. Soul taking its sweet time in
X high mode. You can see the context
window differences. You can see the cost
differences. Fable already what is this
10 times more expensive than soul but
also table 5 is already done here with
its outputs. We're going to see what our
builder puts together here. So very very
simple idea taken to a reasonable level.
Scale your computer to scale your
impact. Great. I've said it a million
times how you can use multiple models at
the same time to solve problems. Great.
You know this. You already know about
delegation. You already know about
spinning up multiple terminal windows.
Everyone's using git work trees
different coding agents. Blah blah blah.
Cmox herder t-mucks. Like that's all
great. What we really want to do here is
combine the intelligence to make the
best possible engineering decisions.
This is where we deviate. This is where
we push a little further than your
classic sub aent delegation. Right?
We're not handing off a task. We have
two agents, really tight-knit team
working together. We want their
opinions. We want to fuse their results
and then we can run auto validate loops
that generate verification and building
at the same time. And as these models
continue to progress and as your harness
engineering, your prompt engineering,
your contact engineering continue to
progress, all of this comes together to
create some insane engineering results.
And this is once again, I just want to
mention this. This is just one node in
your ADWs in your AI developer
workflows. Bloom engineering is the
wrong interpretation. It's the wrong
mental model for understanding what you
should be focused on right now. It's AI
developer workflows. It's your software
factory. Again, check out last week's
video. I'm starting to get the feeling
here that uh soul is going to create an
insane result here. Hopefully, it's
thinking is actually generating value.
Some of these models just chew up
thinking tokens and generate the same or
worse outputs because they're
overthinking it just like you or I might
overthink something, you know, analysis
paralysis. But here we go. SQL bulk
benchmark builder OpenAI GPT 5.6. Here
we go. It's running it. Uh this is going
to be awesome. Using a lot of compute
here to get this result. This is why a
lot of the benchmarks, a lot of the
results still say Fable is in the lead.
The work it does, it just needs fewer
tokens to ship. The simple way to put
it, it's just smarter. Like a great
principal engineer, they know when they
don't have to do work. Knowing when not
to work is just as important, maybe even
more important, than knowing when to
work. It's like when a senior engineer
learns that deleting code is often
better than adding code or modifying
code. Anyways, skip ahead a little bit
for you so I don't waste your time.
There we go. GBD 5.6 took Soul wrapping
up its response here after 8 minutes. So
we have the total run for both of our
agents. You can see here Soul was
actually twice as expensive as Fable,
but now Fable in fusion mode is going to
combine the results. Our architect is
going to look at both results and put
them together. So it sees both source
scripts. It's going to pull them
together and it's going to fuse the
result. So you can see there's the
response from our agents. Looks like we
have max tune gen with an insane 560x
speed up for inserting rows over native
SQL light autocommits. This is the real
power of the fusion harness. It's really
in this/ command. Opinion matters. Autov
validate is a very very powerful pattern
I highly recommend you check out for
solving problems when you want to do
less reviewing and when you trust your
agents, right? Specifically when you
have agents that understand your system,
when you've created a specialized agent,
a custom agent that understands your
system better than others. One of the
key leverage points there is, of course,
the system prompt. You have to overwrite
the system prompt to really guide your
agent to powerful results. But even with
the defaults, you can get really
powerful results out of having a
state-of-the-art model auto validate
another state-of-the-art model. These
capabilities will continue to increase.
I know it sounds a little wacky. You
know, some engineers rightfully so keep
pointing to the error rates when you
keep stacking up these agents. I think
that's fine. that that is only the case
when you haven't templated your
engineering into your system and when
you're not really putting in the effort
to create great prompt context and
harness engineering into your system.
These out of the box agents are
fallible. It is your actual work, your
agent engineering in all these domains,
right? All these subdomains, prompt,
context, harness engineering that really
make up the true value. You can see here
the fusion agent is combining these
results and it's going to use the best
of both worlds. Two state-of-the-art
models beats one. Two state-of-the-art
models where you fuse the best of both
worlds beats two. An auto validation
loop using both agents with all their
context. One to build the validation,
the other to actually build the work.
They iterate on each other beats just a
build test workflow. Once again, scaling
compute to scale your impact. And I
really want to hit on this key theme.
Your agent harness is the body that
transforms compute into intelligence
that works for you. So, whoever owns
your agent harness owns your results.
And this is why, you know, week after
week I keep talking about the PI agent
harness. I don't care if you use a PI
agent harness. Build your own PI agent
harness. Build a tool that does the same
thing. Doesn't matter. The key is like
you want to unblock yourself from being
stuck on codecs, cloud code, open code.
It is the customizability and extensible
design of something like the pi coding
agent that truly differentiates it and
truly differentiates your results. The
workflows that we've looked through here
are just a few, right? There are many
other patterns you can build into your
fusion harness. Couple ideas just to
throw at you. Debate. You can build a
slash debate. Pass in a number. Pass in
a prompt. Pass in a total debate rounds.
So n 10 times, five times, three times.
Have your agents debate an idea or a
concept or an architecture. You can do
like / parallel. And this should just
execute both of your agents at the same
time versus opinion. They're just
responding. Opinion doesn't have right
or edit tools. There's something like uh
you know a coordinate. You give your
agents a task. They talk back and forth
about the solution and then they
actually build it. So this is all in the
realm of harness engineering and in that
there's prompt engineering, there's
context engineering. All of it fits
under the subdomain of agentic
engineering, right? Building valuable
software with agents, with code, and
with engineers as the three units of
value creation. Our agent finish here.
Let's see what the fuse result looks
like. What's the best strategy? So the
speed winner setbased CTE. This is a
combination of builder and architect
solution to get an a,000x speed up. Love
that. Here is our memory winner wallt
tuned generation. Not going to go into
too much of the details here. If you're
a database nerd, uh you'll be able to
look at these results. I'll make sure to
save this in this codebase so you can
take a look at these. But the consensus
divergence, both the models
independently chose subprocess per
strategy isolations, one deterministic
data set, a bunch of stuff. So they
matched up here. They diverged here.
This is really interesting. The builder
solution GBD 5.6 soul was simpler and
faster, but the three column schema was
simpler from the architect. single run
order over median of two shuffled
simpler that was from the architect.
Okay, so there's just a bunch of stuff
here where uh one idea was pulled from
the architect, one idea was pulled from
the builder, one idea was pulled from
the architect, they both got the same
idea, so on and so forth. These
divergences is what makes value. It's
not the fact that you have 10 John's
working on your team. It's the fact that
you have a John, a Sally, Tim, you know,
insert the analogy I'm trying to make,
right? It's the range of perspectives
and the range of ideas on your team of
engineers on your team of agents that
gives you the real value proposition.
Okay. So this is why I say don't choose
compute combine compute thinking ands
not ors. And so you know the last prompt
here is the of course autov validate. It
looks like our agents kind of already
did run this to like really build this
out. I'll kick this off. This runs the
exact same workflow. You know our
validator agent is going to read the
work. It's going to create a
comprehensive gate file that our builder
must run when it finishes. Again, this
is built into the fabric of the fusion
harness. Because we own the Asian
harness, we can make it so that the
builder cannot edit the gate file. And
then if something goes wrong, it'll loop
and our agents will coordinate together.
This is a team. This is not subent
delegation. We have agents working
together to deliver you better results.
So, I'm going to leave this PI coding
agent fusion harness linked in the
description if you're interested in how
to combine models to outperform either.
Just like agents plus code beats agents
alone and agents plus code beats code
alone, multiple agents that fuse their
intelligence beats the agents
standalone. The industry is coming
around to this idea once again. We're
renaming it. I don't care about the
name. I don't care who's writing a blog
post about it. I want you to have these
ideas so that you can scale your
compute, to scale your impact, so that
you can win in the age of agents. This
is another multi-agent orchestration
pattern and it's another node inside of
your ADWs or AI developer workflows. For
those that watched last week's video
that went pretty viral for a deep tech
channel like this, we dismantleed loop
engineering and discussed what we should
really be focusing our agentic
engineering on. And the key topics there
is the software developer life cycle,
ADWs, and software factories. Check out
that video if you haven't because the
fusion harness fits perfectly inside of
a single agent node and it's all making
up what's possible. It's one piece of
the puzzle of the frontier of Agentic.
I'm going to keep pushing this harness
forward as I have several of my other
custom agent harnesses because the value
proposition is there. We've talked about
the verifier agent harness. We've talked
about the CEO agent harness, multi-team
agent harnesses. The frontier is right
in front of us and we're just getting
started. Next week I'm going to dive
into a very very important spicy topic
is really critical for you and I as
engineers building companies building
software building IP that we want to
defend. We're going to ask and answer
the question as long as nothing else you
know more important comes up. This
landscape is so crazy. I want to dial
into this question is anthropic and open
AI stealing our data while we pay for
it. Stealing our IP, our valuable
prompts, our valuable business
workflows, are they stealing it while we
pay them for it? Of course, this leads
directly into the conversation about
Chinese models, about US openweight
models, so on and so forth. That's the
topic for next week. If you made it this
far into the video, huge thanks to you.
Make sure you like, make sure you
subscribe, all that good stuff. Make
sure you comment, let the algorithm know
you're interested in true agentic
engineering on this channel. We don't
just clickbait the news. We think, plan,
and build to progress our engineering in
the age of agents. Our Fable 5 validator
just finished this [music] nice massive
validation script so that once it runs,
we know for a fact the code is going to
work. There is the initial pass fail
[music] and now our builder is getting
to work actually creating the script.
I'm not going to hold you here for this.
I'll make sure to add the result into
the codebase. Again, link in the
description for you. We have a lot of
really important concepts to discuss on
the channel coming up. So, be sure to
like, subscribe, comment, all that good
stuff so the algorithm doesn't miss you.
You know where to find me every single
Monday. Stay focused and keep building.